Ushindi Bienvenu

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

jeanbienvenusb@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn | Twitter | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced Full-Stack Web Developer with a proven 4-year track record in helping companies build effective and optimized web solutions. Seeking a collaborative team environment that fosters learning and growth opportunities, with a focus on developing leadership skills over time.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PHP, Laravel, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql **Tools & Methods**: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD **Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Detail-oriented

EXPERIENCE

JUUBIX Remote

Software Engineer

Sept 2023 - Present

- Involved in designing and implementing a matching algorithm that matches prospective parties based on common data points for a custom web platform.
- Collaborated with UX/UI designers to transform wireframes and mockups into fully functional software solutions, ensuring a seamless user experience and adherence to design principles.
- Fostered a culture of accountability and instilled collective responsibility for development milestones and deliverables by orchestrating regular team syncs.

MICROVERSE Remote

Code Reviewer

Oct 2022 - Dec 2023

- Successfully conducted code and UI reviews for over 600 students, providing feedback and guidance to help them become better software developers.
- Collaborated with the technical team to develop and implement new coding standards and best practices.
- Researched and implemented new technologies and tools to improve the company's code review process.

Mentor July 2022 - Oct 2022

- Advised and motivated students to stay in the program, leading to a high retention rate.
- Collaborated with other Student Mentors to foster an environment of learning and mentorship.
- Implemented new strategies to guide students on how to improve their coding skills.

FREELANCE

Full-stack Developer

Jan 2020 - April 2022

- Developed a secure shop management system for a client that enabled them to manage their operations more effectively.
- Built a cross-cultural marketplace for Congo and Uganda.

HARVAN INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE

Kampala, Uganda

Full Stack Web Developer

February 2019 - June 2019

- Implemented a comprehensive website design that improved the company's online presence and visibility.
- Analyzed and suggested content that meets the organization's requirements.
- Developed a comprehensive suite of website optimization techniques, including CDN implementation, image compression, and minified CSS and JS files, resulting in a 30% reduction in page load times.

INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF EAST AFRICA Front-End Web Developer

Kampala, Uganda June 2019 – February 2020

- Implemented a comprehensive website design that improved the company's online presence and visibility.
- Utilized SEO best practices to improve the website's competitiveness in search engine rankings.
- Collaborated with marketing teams to create targeted campaigns that increased website traffic and customer loyalty.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE March 2022 - December 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

International University of East Africa

January 2015 - November 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

• Designed and implemented an emergency tracking and response system.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Threadify - <u>Demo</u> Make Twitter thread creation easier. Allows users to create a numbered Twitter thread in no time.

Sharingan- Demo knowledge based system that helps code reviewers quickly search for specific code review guidelines and generate a ready to use comment for each requirement that is not followed.

For more projects you can visit my portfolio website.